Guide to the Department of Geography, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of Geography, Yale University, records
1945-1977
RU 715
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
5
(4 boxes)
The records consist of correspondence, financial records, and printed material documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Geography, which no longer exists as a separate academic unit.
Yale University. Dept. of Geography
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Siences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See inventory for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, financial records, and printed material documenting the activities and operations of the Yale Department of Geography, which no longer exists as a separate academic unit.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by type of material.
Geography -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University. Dept. of Geography
- Records, 1945-1977; Accession 1977-A-004
  - Departmental files by subject, including:
    - Geography Dept. plans and reports, 1945-1965, undated (Box 1, Folder 1 - 3)
    - Administrative files, 1963-1968, undated (Box 1, Folder 4 - 5)
    - General correspondence, 1957-1967 (Box 1, Folder 6 - 8)
    - University: general matters, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9 - 10)
    - FOFIRP (Foreign Field Research Program) Screening, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Huntington Library, 1948-1960 (Box 1, Folder 12 - 13)
    - Provost, 1955-1972 (Box 1, Folder 14 - 15)
    - Various conferences, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 16 - 22)
  - Financial Records
    - Department budget correspondence, 1948-1960 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Budget statements, 1958-1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ledger accounts, 1951-1965 June (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - General appropriations, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Requisitions, 1952-1966 June (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Delivery slips, 1951-1960 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Purchase orders, 1951-1960 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Bills, 1951-1963 April (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Folders of miscellaneous financial records, supplies and equipment (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Faculty and staff files
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted until January 1, 2050
    - Staff general files (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Staff individual files (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Applications for positions within the department (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Academic Files
    Restricted until January 1, 2051
    - Yale College and undergraduate subjects (Box 4, Folder 35)
    - Graduate School and related subjects (Box 4, Folder 36)
    - Departmental files, examinations, courses, majors (Box 4, Folder 37)
    - Individual student files (Box 4, Folder 38)
    - Student inquiries about Geography Department (Box 4, Folder 39)
    - Bursary students (Box 4, Folder 40)